KABUKICHO
Processed by 繁化姬 dict-74c8d060-r1048 @ 2024/04/06 14:46:33 | https://zhconvert.org
DIVINATION
(占卜)
Is it okay if I fill out this questionnaire in this manner?
问卷调查应该可以这样填吧
I think it should be okay.
我觉得可以
Is the divination here really that accurate?
这里的占卜真的很准吗
Yes, it's really accurate.
很准的
-Really? -Yes.
-真的吗 这位小哥 -真的
This is my second visit here.
我这是第二次来了
After listening to his divination last time,
上次听完他的占卜后我就确信了
I was convinced that the diviner here is a true professional.
这里的占卜师是真正的占卜师
He even mentioned my injured foot,
他甚至还说出了
which only my colleagues knew about.
关于我的脚受伤的事 这可只有我的同事才知道呢
Wow, I'm so excited!
哇啊 太期待了
So, what did you find?
话说 你查到什么了吗
I spent the entire night investigating that sign,
我花了一整晚的时间调查那个符号
and the information I found was intricate and complex.
查到的情报却错综复杂
However, I always feel like
不过我总感觉
it seems to involve internal police affairs, making it difficult.
这似乎还涉及到了公安内部 是个十分棘手的案件
Moreover, Prosecutor Hosorogi disappeared at a crucial moment
而且 细吕木监察官
while investigating this matter.
就是在追查到这件事的关键时失踪的
WELL, ALTHOUGH MOST OF IT IS CORRECT, I WAS ALMOST KILLED WHEN I WAS ABOUT TO CATCH HIM, AND THEN ENDED UP LIKE THIS
(好吧 虽然大部分是正确的)
THE ASSASSIN THEY HIRED SHOULD HAVE KILLED ME IN THIS BUILDING
(应该是他们雇的暗杀者在这栋楼里把我杀害的)
That means…
也就是说…
Since even the prosecutor was alarmed,
既然连监察官都惊动了
doesn't it indicate that the criminal is within the police force?
这是不是说明犯人就在警察内部呢
SORRY, I CAN'T GIVE YOU MORE INFORMATION UNTIL WE'RE SURE WHO THE CULPRIT IS. IT WOULD IMPLICATE YOU ALL
(抱歉 在还不确定谁是犯人的情况下 我不能告诉你们更多信息了 这样会牵连到你们的)
But haven't we already been involved in all of this?
不 我们这不都已经 被完全牵扯进来了吗
I'm actually fine.
我倒是没关系
If it causes problems for the real Polka and the Shinoyama family…
但如果给真波尔卡以及 四乃山家的人带来麻烦的话…
Hmm, you also care about their safety, right?
嗯 你也很在意她们的安危吧
YES, THAT'S RIGHT. "ACT WITH CAUTION" MEANS EXACTLY THAT
(是啊 所谓“小心行事”指的就是这个意思)
This is indeed related to that person named Hosorogi.
这果然和那个叫细吕木的人有关系
Could there be an issue within the police force?
难道是警察内部有问题吗
Who exactly are these mischievous kids
这群坏小子
fighting against?
他们究竟在与什么人为敌
Xiaoyu, I'm hungry.
小幽 我饿了
I will prepare food for you right away.
我马上就为您准备食物
However, they have always had awkward pauses during their conversation,
不过 他们对话时 总是会有不自然的停顿
and I have also heard the sound of a pencil writing.
而且 我还听到 有自动铅笔写字的声音
I HAVE ALREADY TOLD THE PEOPLE WHO NEED TO KNOW WHAT NEEDS TO BE SAID
(该说的事 我都已经告诉给该知道的人了)
Are you referring to the police officer named Iwanome?
你说的是那个叫岩野目的警察吗
ALTHOUGH THIS IS SOMETHING UNFINISHED ON MY PART,
(这虽然是我未尽之事)
I CAN ONLY TRUST HIM, WHO HAS SEARCHED TOGETHER WITH ME, WITH THIS CASE
(但这个案子只有拜托给 和我一起搜查过的那家伙我才能放心)
(Dead Mount, Death Play)
《尸体如山的死亡游戏》
In conclusion,
综上所述
(TENA SORIMURA, SPECIAL INVESTIGATION DEPARTMENT) Solitaire is incredibly elusive.
(雪车村天鸦 特别搜查本部) 雪天鸦十分神出鬼没
As the person in charge of this investigation,
作为本次调查的负责人
I am well aware that my description is not precise.
我非常清楚我这样的描述是不严谨的
(TENA SORIMURA, SELF-PROCLAIMED MAGICIAN) However, based on
(雪车村天鸦 自称魔术师) 但通过刚才的介绍
the introduction just now,
我相信各位已经能理解
I believe you all can understand the reasons why I have to express it this way.
我不得不这样表达的原因了
However, we have found that the suspect has a habit of
不过 我们发现 嫌疑人对于自己感兴趣的目标
actively approaching and observing targets that interest him.
有主动去接近和观察的习惯
In other words,
也就是说
as long as we investigate the sign he has set his sights on,
只要追查他盯上的这个标志
there is a high probability that we will encounter Solitaire.
我们就很有可能会遇上雪天鸦
-People from the Shinjuku Police Station are here too. -Next, please refer to page 12 of the documents.
-新宿警察局的人怎么也来了 -接下来请各位看资料第12页…
Even Arase and Tozawa are here.
连荒濑和户泽老兄也来了
This group of troublemakers has all gathered together.
这群爱惹麻烦的家伙全聚一起了
Previously, they and the prosecutor caused havoc within the police organization.
之前他们和监察官一起 把警察组织内部闹得一团糟
And now they actually have the audacity to show up in front of us.
事到如今竟还有脸出现在我们面前
DIVINATION, OPEN FROM 10 A.M.
(占卜 早上十点开始接待)
Shota Yamanoura.
山之浦章太先生
You are currently at the crossroads of destiny.
你现在正处于命运的十字路口
I can sense the fluctuations.
我感觉到了那股波动
The ship you are on
你所在的这艘船
is about to collide with a hidden reef adorned with illusory grandeur.
即将撞到一个 被虚幻的华丽装饰所点缀的暗礁上
Before it sinks,
在它沉没之前
it would be best for you to find another ship where you can seek refuge.
你最好找到另一艘可以容身的船
You managed to guess everything correctly,
我根本没把这些事写在问卷调查里
even though I didn't mention any of it in the questionnaire.
而你居然全说中了
However, these are all the experiences
不过 这些都是真正的山之浦章太
(SPECIAL LECTURE: THREE BIG SECRETS OF THE WORKING CLASS! 1. HE IS ACTUALLY TENA SORIMURA!) of the real Shota Yamanoura.
(特别讲解 上班族的三大秘密! 一 其实他是雪天鸦) 他的经历罢了
(2. HE USED SPECIAL DISGUISE TECHNIQUES COMPARABLE TO HOLLYWOOD MOVIES (SELF-TAUGHT)) (3. THE REAL YAMANOURA IS JUST AN ORDINARY PERSON AND HAS NOTHING TO DO WITH SOLITAIRE!)
(二 他用了堪比好莱坞大片的特殊易容妆(自学))
What he said was nothing more than a hot reading technique.
刚刚他所说的这些都只不过是热读术
All of these should have been done by Takumi Kuruya,
这些应该都是婆婆说的那个骇客
the hacker that Granny talked about.
缲屋匠的杰作吧
He was able to uncover falsification of accounts of Mr. Yamanoura's company
他能够在短时间内调查到 山之浦先生公司在做假账的事
in a short period of time, even before it was reported in the news.
而且是在新闻都还没报道的情况下
This is truly remarkable.
这点真是了不起
But what's disappointing is this diviner.
但令人失望的是 这个占卜师
He's just an ordinary person.
应该只是个普普通通的人而已吧
Huh, were my words just now really that hurtful?
咦 我刚才的话有这么令人挫折吗
Well, alright.
不过 好吧 接下来
Do you have any more questions?
你还有什么想问的问题吗
Other things I wanted to ask…
其他我想问的事吗
Well…
这个嘛
Recently, there has been a lot of buzz about Solitaire.
最近那个雪天鸦
He promised to offer 300 million yen to anyone who solved that sign's puzzle?
他不是说如果有人能解开 那个符号的谜题 就给他三亿日元吗
I wonder if you could use divination to find out the origin of that sign.
不知能我否请你用占卜 看一下那个符号是什么来头
This is beyond my divination.
这个 我确实有些无能为力了
I know it's not possible given your abilities.
也是 我就知道以你的能力应该不行
However...
不过
I can sense that the sign is a bit peculiar.
我能感觉到那个符号有些古怪
Peculiar?
古怪
It seems to have been added with something extra.
它似乎被加上了什么多余的东西
Now I will use the profound power of wandering souls' destiny in this world
现在我将借助游荡于世间的 灵魂宿命之力
to discover its true shape.
找出它的原形
What?
什么
Wow, this is really something.
哦 这还真不得了
These strong lines do not appear to be controlled by threads or magnets.
从这强有力的线条力度来看 不像是用线和磁铁控制的
Compared to divination,
比起占卜 这更能勾起我
this arouses more interest in me as a magician.
作为一个魔术师的兴趣
The original sign
本来的这个符号
was missing a horizontal stroke.
是少了一横的
This is my final divination result.
这就是我最终的占卜结果
Gotcha!
上钩啦
I actually managed to find it.
竟然真的让我找到了
Wait a moment.
不不不 等一下
If he is truly a member of the mysterious organization,
要是他真是神秘组织的人的话
how could he reveal such information to me so easily?
怎么会如此轻易地 透漏这种信息给我呢
I need to stay calm! This must be some kind of test on me!
我要冷静 这一定是对我的某种试探
I got it.
我明白
If I keep talking, I'll be doubted. So let's stop here.
再继续说下去的话 我就会被怀疑了 所以就到此为止吧
However, I also have my own principles.
只不过我也有自己的坚持
I cannot simply turn a blind eye
对于这个被误写的符号
to this misdrawn sign.
我做不到视而不见
However, unless I point out to Solitaire personally, it has no significance.
不过如果不是向雪天鸦本人指出的话 也没什么意义就是了
CRITICAL HIT
(会心一击)
Is that so?
是…是吗
I will take it as a reference.
我会作为参考的
Then I'll take my leave.
那么我就告辞了
-Oh, there's one more thing. -What is it?
-哦 最后还有一件事 -什么
Do you have an impression of
你对一位坐在轮椅上
a girl sitting in a wheelchair with braided hair?
梳着辫子的女孩有印象吗
I couldn't make out what she was saying.
我无法听出她在说些什么
But she seemed to show concern
但她似乎对你现在的所行之路
about the path you were on.
表现出了担忧
Her spirit body actually took the shape of a wheelchair.
她的灵体竟然呈现出了轮椅的形状
This only happens if one spends a lot of time in a wheelchair.
这是只有长时间坐轮椅才会有的现象
But I can't talk to her anymore.
不过我现在已经无法和她对话了
It should be my guardian spirit or something like that.
应该是我的守护灵之类的吧
I will think about it
我会回去好好想想
and come up with a solution.
然后寻找解决方法的
Then it appears that I do not need to force her to ascend to heaven.
那看来我还是不要强行帮她升天了
You have succeeded in arousing my interest, Diviner.
你成功引起了我的兴趣 占卜师先生
I thought he was just a fraud
我本以为他只是个用热读术
who used hot reading to pretend to have supernatural powers.
装作有特异功能的骗子
But how did he know about the kid?
但他是怎么知道那孩子的事的
What exactly did he see?
他到底 看到了什么
Wow, it really lives up to its reputation.
哇啊 真是名不虚传啊
He is adorable.
他长得真可爱啊
You only pay attention to the appearance.
你就只知道看脸
Ah, it's raining.
啊 下雨了
Oops, I didn't bring an umbrella.
糟糕 我没有带伞
Then let me lend you my umbrella. I still have my raincoat.
那把我的借你用吧 我还有雨衣呢
If I get caught in the rain, my disguise makeup will be ruined.
淋到雨的话我的易容妆就毁了
I really admire the energy of young people.
唉 我还真羡慕年轻人的活力
I see.
原来如此
You seem to have noticed this as much as I did.
看来你和我一样都注意到了这一点
However, it is a coincidence
不过 说起来还真巧啊
that I was asked the same question twice today.
今天居然有两个人 连续问了我同样的问题
But, speaking of which,
不过话说回来
(EXERCISE CAUTION WITH FIRE) I cannot stand the girl's
(小心火烛) 那姑娘选雨衣的品味
choice of raincoat.
我还真是欣赏不来
SAKURAMONDA STATION
(樱田门站)
We have dispatched hundreds of investigators
关于雪天鸦的调查
to conduct road inspections
我们派出了上百名调查员 分别采取了道路盘查
and retrieve surveillance footage
调取监控等方式
in order to pinpoint Solitaire's movements.
来锁定他的行动范围
However, we still do not know
然而 我们还是不知道
what his ultimate objective is.
他的目的到底是什么
His current interest is…
他现在最感兴趣的是…
(TENA SORIMURA, SELF-PROCLAIMED MAGICIAN)
(雪车村天鸦 自称魔术师)
Do we want to lure the snake out of its hole?
我们要引蛇出洞吗
Only a very few people know about
那个符号和原来的形状不同这件事
the difference between that sign and the original one.
只有极少数的人才知道
But this matter cannot be disclosed here, right?
但是 这件事不能在这里公开 是吗
Yes. We still don't know who the enemy is.
是啊 现在我们还不知道敌人在哪里
Whoever made that person disappear without a trace must be a formidable opponent.
毕竟能让那个人消失踪影的 一定是个强劲的对手
If we casually drop the bait now, there's a possibility of being counterattacked.
如果现在就轻易放下诱饵 只会让我们被反噬而已
Although my primary job is to investigate the whereabouts of Solitaire,
虽然我的本职工作 是调查雪天鸦的下落
if I try to focus on more than one thing, it will throw me off track.
但若同时兼顾多个目标 就会扰乱我的思绪
Once Solitaire is captured, progress will be made on all other matters.
只要抓到了雪天鸦 其他的事就都会有进展的
And you should be pleased
而且现在能调动的人手增加了
that there are more people available to be mobilized.
你应该高兴才是
You exhaust us
就知道让我们做牛做马
while you sip your coffee.
你自己却在喝咖啡
Someone who once lagged behind in his career
一个曾在职业道路上掉队的人
has unexpectedly made it to the top.
现在竟然出人头地了
Thank you for your compliment.
多谢夸奖
Thanks to your blessings,
托您的福 我现在至少有权力
I now have at least the authority to command you all.
可以指挥你们了
Moreover, since you still have the energy to complain to me,
而且 既然你们还有精力在我这抱怨
it seems that you haven't reached the level of being completely exhausted.
说明也没有到做牛做马的程度吧
Don't get too carried away.
你少得意忘形
You were Hosorogi's sidekick before this. You had many detractors.
你之前不过就是细吕木的小跟班 讨厌你的人可有得是
Oh, I see.
啊 是这样啊
I thought that those corrupt police officers
我还以为会因为 内部审查的事而怨恨我的
who can no longer openly engage in private misconduct
只有那些不能再
would be the only ones to resent me because of the internal review.
公然营私舞弊的无良警察们呢
Be clear about your status
我是让你搞清自己的身份
and behave properly within your jurisdiction
在自己的管辖区好好待着
instead of swaggering around here.
少在我们这里耀武扬威的
Why do you always rely on your official titles to make a point?
动不动就拿官职头衔来说事
Are you so insecure that you can't speak without them?
不这样你们就心虚到无法说话了吗
What a ridiculous habit.
这是什么臭毛病啊
Even junior high school students on the internet are better than you.
网上那些初中生们都比你们强
What did you say?
你说什么
Calm down.
别激动啊
What are you doing? Let go of me.
你干什么…放手
Arase, I'm fine.
荒濑 我没事
Arase.
荒濑
I told you that I am fine.
我已经说了我没事
Folks,
前辈们
let's refrain from engaging in such acts of bullying the weak, alright?
我们还是都别再干这种 恃强凌弱的事了吧
Arase, don't forget that
荒濑 你可别忘了
you have previously conducted an illegal undercover search.
你之前还非法进行过卧底搜查
You should be well aware of the consequences if any trouble arises again.
要是再闹出什么麻烦 你觉得自己会是什么下场
We have the ability to fabricate charges against you out of thin air if we wish.
只要我们想 给你凭空捏造一个罪名也不是不可以
No way. I've already been punished for the undercover investigation.
这可不行啊 关于卧底搜查的事 我已经受过处分了
Mr. Tozawa gave me a severe reprimand as well.
我还被户泽先生狠狠教训了一顿呢
Ah, I found you!
啊 找到了找到了
Mr. Iwa, I did not expect you to be slacking around and picking fights.
没想到你在这偷懒 还跟人找碴呢 岩先生
Oh dear, be careful.
哎呀 小心
Are you okay?
你没事吧
Oh dear, is this the way you fabricate false charges?
哎呀 这难道就是你所谓的 捏造罪名的方式吗
It's truly vexing.
真让人头疼啊
You took advantage of being tripped and purposefully dislocated your own shoulder.
你居然趁跌倒时 故意把自己的肩膀弄脱臼了
Fortunately, I'm here to help you fix it.
幸好有我在 还能帮你修复好
If it were Arase, he wouldn't know how to handle it.
要是荒濑的话 可能就不知道该怎么处理了
It's fixed.
这样问题就解决了
SHINJUKU POLICE'S COMMUNITY SAFETY DIVISION, ASSISTANT MANAGER OF MATERIALS COMPILING GROUP NO.3, DANJO TOZAWA
(新宿警署生活安全课)
Ah, what a stroke of luck!
啊 真是万幸啊
Fortunately, nothing major happened.
幸好没出什么大事
ALSO A MEMBER OF MATERIALS COMPILING GROUP NO.3, WINNER OF THE SHINJUKU POLICE STATION ARREST TACTICS TOURNAMENT INDIVIDUAL COMPETITION, RANMARU YATSU
(同属第三资料编辑系)
I JUST STOPPED ARASE IN A COOL WAY, DIDN'T I?
(我刚才很帅气地阻止了荒濑对吧?)
POP TOZAWA, YOU SAW IT TOO, RIGHT?
(户泽大叔你们也看见了吧?)
What are you all doing?
你们在做什么
Isn't this Chief Superintendent Habaki?
这不是幅木警视署长吗
Nothing serious.
没什么啦
We're just providing emergency treatment
我们只是在给跌倒的同事
to our colleague who fell down.
紧急处理一下伤势而已
Isn't that right?
对吧
Yes, it is.
是…是的
Then we'll take our leave.
那我们就告辞了
So, what exactly happened, Iwanome?
然后呢 到底发生了什么事 岩野目
I get the whole situation.
我了解事情原委了
Although those guys were at fault first,
虽然是那帮家伙有错在先
you shouldn't provoke them too much either.
但你也不要过多地挑衅他们
The Solitaire video incident has caused police unrest.
警局内部本就因为 雪天鸦的视频 而人心惶惶了
You mean that there is a traitor, right?
你的意思是说有内奸吗
Yes, the higher-ups
是啊 上层领导
seemed to believe that the sniper incident was orchestrated by Solitaire himself.
似乎认定了狙击事件 是雪天鸦自导自演的
But it's better for you to avoid trouble as much as possible.
不过 你尽量还是少惹事
Even in my position, I have limited ability to protect you.
即使在我这个位置 能对你的袒护也是有限的
I am grateful
您能够稍微袒护我一下
even if you can only provide me with limited protection.
我已经十分感激了
I'll take my leave then.
那么 我就告辞了
You need to be more careful.
你要多加小心啊
Although it's currently just my speculation,
这次的事
this matter may be related to
虽然目前只是我的推测
the Lemmings and other calamities.
但有可能和旅鼠军团 还有其他灾厄有关
That's truly frightening.
那还真是可怕
So, the more trustworthy people we have, the better.
所以我们可以信任的人手 最好越多越好
-Old man. -Well.
-大叔 -哎呀
I was actually going to tell you
我本来还想跟你们说 让你们不要加深
not to deepen the conflict between you and headquarters.
和总部之间的矛盾呢
I think that person simply dislikes you.
我看刚才那个人 只是单纯地讨厌岩先生你吧
Whatever, Yatsu.
随你怎么说 八津
However, our Comps-3 mission remains unchanged,
不过 不管怎样 我们三辑要做的事一直没有变
which is to wholeheartedly protect the city's safety.
那就是全心全意守护城市的安全
We have to fight against
和那帮疯狂的
those crazy calamities until the end.
灾厄们对抗到底
I can't believe even the Lei family's intelligence network
居然连雷家的情报网
couldn't find the whereabouts of Hosorogi.
都查不出细吕木的下落
Footsteps on the roof?
屋顶传来了脚步声
Oh, every time I land from the roof,
呜呼 每次从屋顶降落
I feel incredibly excited.
都让我感到无比地兴奋
This excitement stems from the guilt of committing a crime
这种兴奋来自于 自己将要犯下罪行的罪恶感
or
亦或是
the tension of potential enemies lurking ahead.
前方或许有敌人正埋伏着的紧张感
No, no, not at all!
非也 非也非也
It is a kind of intoxication.
这是一种陶醉
Since the copyright to the works
既然那位大作家
of the great writer Edogawa Ranpo has also expired,
江户川乱步的著作权也已经过期了
I suppose I can even call myself "The Fiend with Twenty Faces"
那么就算我自称怪人二十面相
without causing offense.
也不算是冒犯吧
Hold on a moment.
不 等一下
This could be considered offensive to fans of Ranpo, right?
这对乱步迷来说应该算是种冒犯吧
AND IT SEEMED QUITE OFFENSIVE…
(而且好像相当冒犯他们…)
What do you think?
你是怎么认为的呢
I didn't expect such a warm welcome right from the start.
没想到一上来 你就这么热烈地欢迎我
It seems my intuition is correct.
看来我的直觉是正确的
So, can you please tell me
那么 接下来能请你告诉我
have you been affiliated with any particular organization?
你究竟是跟哪个组织有关联吗
And tell me about that sign!
还有关于那个符号的事
Corpse God diviner.
占卜师“尸神殿”
No, I should call you Polka Shinoyama!
不 我应该叫你四乃山波尔卡才对
Please do not compare me to that weak guy.
请不要把我 和那个软弱的家伙相提并论
Who are you?
你是谁
AT THAT TIME, POLKA
(此时的波尔卡)
Bamboo cage, bamboo cage.
竹笼缝 竹笼缝
Oh, little bird in the cage,
笼中的鸟儿啊
when will you come out?
何时何时出来呢
On the eve of dawn,
即将天明的晚上
both the crane and the turtle slipped.
鹤与龟都滑倒了
Who is the person behind me?
身后的人是谁呢…
Hurry up! The army has been devoured by the sinkhole.
快点 陆军已经被“洞穴”吞噬了
Where is General Daryl?
达里尔将军在哪里
Their entire force has been taken away by the Lewd and Cruel Dragon!
他们整支部队 都被“淫虐龙”带走了
Did they escape? That's why I said not to trust the Dragon Clan.
他们逃跑了吗 所以我之前就说不能相信龙族
-What about the Prince and the Queen? -What are you doing, foolish apprentice?
-皇子和皇后殿下呢 -你在干什么 笨蛋徒弟
There are barriers around us that hinder understanding.
我们身边设有阻碍认知的结界
Otherwise, we would definitely be involved and sent to the front line.
不然这种时候 我们肯定会被牵连去到前线了
You ask why I don't go?
你问我为什么不去吗
I simply don't want to destroy myself with that bunch of foolish people.
我可不想和那帮愚蠢的人一起毁灭
I've asked Romelka to help as many people as possible that we know well.
我已经让罗梅卡 去尽可能帮助我们熟识的人了
What Utsurojuza said is right. It's time to stop.
“虚铳座”的那帮家伙们说得对 是时候收手了
You should also get ready.
你也去准备一下吧
You ask what I get ready for?
你说准备什么
Get ready to break free from the shackles of the Empire
准备摆脱帝国的束缚
and live a free life from now on.
从此过上自由的生活啊
I have already made you
你这孩子
possess the bones of an elderly person,
都已经让你附身在老年人的骨头上了
but your mentality still resembles that of a child.
但你的心智还总是跟个孩子似的
Forget it.
算了
You will gradually mature in the future.
今后你会慢慢成长的
We have unlimited time.
我们有无限的时间
However, in contrast,
不过与之相对的
we should try our best to cherish
我们要尽量去珍惜
those who live within a limited time frame.
那些活在有限时间里的人
I'm sorry.
是啊 对不起
I'm sorry, Master.
对不起 师父
I failed to act according to your instructions.
我没能遵照您的嘱托行事
I failed to protect them,
我没能保护好他们
failed to save them,
没能救下他们
and failed to let go of this matter.
也没能从心里放下这件事
I have tarnished the abilities you imparted to me.
我玷污了师父传授给我的能力
I am ashamed to face the people of the Empire.
我无颜面对帝国的人民
I have become the enemy of the world.
我成了全世界的敌人
I have escaped from my own world.
我逃离了自己的世界
I no longer have the ability to cherish anything.
我已经没有能力去怜爱什么了
You are still so foolish,
你还是那么笨啊
my dear friend.
我的挚友
Your Majesty.
陛…下…
Alright, alright, I have already awakened.
好了好了 我已经醒了
It seems like there's a smell of something burnt.
好像有股烧焦的味道
What is it?
这是…
Are you still afraid of ghosts?
你现在还怕鬼吗
No, if it's the work of a ghost, I can sense it.
不 如果是幽灵的杰作的话 我能够感应到
It's still warm.
还是温热的
Hello there.
喂你好
Are you Polka Shinoyama?
你是…四乃山…波尔卡吗
Who are you?
你是哪位
Hello?
喂？
Are you…
你…也是…
a product of Sabaramond as well?
“塞巴拉隆多的产物”…吗
Why? Why do you know this name?
为什么 你为什么会知道这个名字
So that's how it is.
原来是这么回事啊
They're really malicious,
“他们”还真是坏心眼啊
dragging me into this destined prank.
居然把我卷进这命运的恶作剧中
"They"? Who are you referring to?
“他们” 你说的是谁
I recall this guy is the wanted criminal everyone is talking about right now.
我记得这家伙好像是 现在大家都在讨论的通缉犯吧
He didn't even react!
他竟然毫无反应
Who exactly is this child?
这小孩到底是谁
Despite my mysterious speech, I do not know what to do next.
虽然我先试着说了些故弄玄虚的话 但接下来完全不知道该怎么办
I need to calm down and think.
我要冷静思考
Forget it.
算了
Once I catch you,
等抓住你后
I'll slowly interrogate you.
我再慢慢拷问就是了
Don't be in such a hurry, young man.
别这么着急嘛 少年
You're still young.
你年纪还小
It's already 3 a.m.,
现在已经凌晨三点了
and the child should go back to sleep.
小孩子应该回去睡觉…
I'm already nineteen years old.
我已经十九岁了
So fast!
好快
Indeed, this is definitely not something a child could be capable of,
这确实不像一个孩子能有的身手
but it's not at a level where it's unavoidable.
但还没有到无法躲避的程度…
Huh?
咦
Has he started to act?
他开始行动了吗
However, it is slightly different from what we expected.
不过 这和我们预想的有些许不同
I didn't expect that the joyful offender
没想到那个愉快犯
would actually fight with my grandpa's personal bodyguard.
居然会和我爷爷的直属护卫打了起来
Let's start taking action as well.
我们也开始行动吧
How can we reap the benefits
在一场混战中
in the midst of a melee?
如何才能坐享渔翁之利
This often plays a crucial role
这往往对控制混乱的局面
in controlling chaotic situations.
有着至关重要的作用